Seth Akkerman

seth@sethakkerman.com www.sethakkerman.com I am an Associate Creative Director / Senior Designer who likes to laugh with people. I have an insatiable curiosity and a desire to leave things better than I found them. I have a background in user experience design, user interface design, and design systems.

EXPERIENCE

(513) 515-2207

DESIGNORY, Chicago, Illinois

Associate Creative Director, Interaction - April 2020-October 2023

Designed large-scale design systems for globally recognized companies (TikTok, Expedia, Organon, Amazon Music) and led a team of exceptional interaction designers. Developed and designed custom Figma plugins to allow automation and expedite internal processes.

GAUGE, Savannah, Georgia – Working Remotely from Chicago, Illinois

UI and UX Designer, Illustrator, Motion Designer - October 2016-February 2020

Designed eCommerce websites for a variety of industries. Prototyped websites for client presentations and internal development hand off. Designed and illustrated marketing materials for client websites, email, and social media. Illustrated and animated articles written by Gauge team.

FREELANCE DESIGNER, Chicago, Illinois

Designer, Art Director, Illustrator, Motion Designer - July 2009-Present

Select clients include OldTimeCandy.com, Two Tides Brewing Co., SF Weekly, Mike Doughty, The Pinyan Company, Telfair Museums, and Rowan Converse / Nocturne Records.

For a complete work history, view bit.ly/seth-on-linkedin.

EDUCATION

SAVANNAH COLLEGE OF ART AND DESIGN, Savannah, Georgia

Graphic Design - Masters of Fine Arts, August 2009

UNIVERSITY OF CINCINNATI, Cincinnati, Ohio

Architectural Engineering Technology - Bachelor of Science, Cum Laude, June 2005

SKILLS

Figma, Sketch, XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects, Premiere, InVision Prototyping, CSS, HTML5, jQuery, JavaScript, Git, GitHub, SAS, Cinema 4D Lite, Processing

PUBLISHED

IdN Magazine, Volume 17, Number 5, 2010 - Spay and Neuter Commercial Featured
Designing Sustainable Packaging, Author: Scott Boylston, Bird Feeder Packaging Featured

AWARDS

2018 Print Magazine Regional Design Annual - Two Tides Brewing Co.
2010 Print Magazine Print in Motion - Finalist - Where the Wild Things Are
2010 ADDY Award - Silver - Telfair Ball Invitations

2009 UCDA Design Competition - Gold Medalist - Savannah Secession Series

SCAD Savannah Secession Graphic Design Exhibition Planning Committee (2008–2009)

INVOLVEMENT / VOLUNTEERING

Creative Mornings Chicago - Director of Marketing (2020–2023)

Creative Mornings Chicago - Event Day Volunteer (2019–2023)

ETHChicago - Brand and NFT Designer (2023)

AIGA - Member (2006-present)

Type Director's Club - Member (2008-present)